DO VUONG PHUC

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

(+84) 707 953 475

■ 16th Oct, 2001

• HCM City, Ward 16, District 8

in phuc16102001

phuc16102001

k phuc16102001

<u>**)** phuc16102001</u>

ABOUT ME

A backend engineer with 3 YoE in software engineer field. I am goal-oriented, dedicated to my work, and always open to new experiences, especially those related to my field of study, to enhance my coding practice.

I have gained many from being a leader of group projects, which is why problem-solving, presentation and leadership skills are not weaknesses of mine. I have a strong passion for software engineering and computer science.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

University of Science (HCMUS)

Artificial Intelligent major | 2019 - 2023

- Bachelor in Information Technology (GPA: 3.94/4)
- Graduated valedictorian (Top 1)

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Valedictorian graduated with the highest GPA
- Top-rated lancer with job success rate of 100%
- Scholarship for the excellent student each semester
- Step STEM Alive Singapore 4th Runner-up prize
- Excellent Students in Informatics Contest 3rd prize
- 30/4 Olympic contest 2018 Gold medal
- 30/4 Olympic contest 2017 Gold medal

LANGUAGE

• English: IELTS Academic Certificate 6.5 (B2 level)

SKILLS

Programming language

• Java, Python, Rust, JavaScript, C++

Software engineering

- Spring, Jenkins, SonarQube, Grafana, Slack Bolt
- Docker, Helm chart, Kubernetes (K8S), Nginx
- MySQL, Postgre, MongoDB, Firebase, Cloudinary
- ReactJS, ExpressJS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Ant Design
- GitHub, CI/CD, Swagger, Jira, Trello, Figma

Distributed system

- Elastic search (ELK), Kafka, Redis
- ZooKeeper, HDFS, Airflow, Spark, Hive

Machine learning

- WEKA, KNIME, Tableau, PowerBI, Sk-learn
- PySpark, PyTorch, TensorFlow

WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend Engineer

Naver Vietnam | Korea market | March 2023 - Present

- Design and develop large-scale zero-downtime systems with millions users.
- Using Java Spring & distributed systems on Naver cloud to implement social media platforms (Naver BBoom and Naver Blog).
- Responsible with DevOps task (e.g. build CI/CD pipeline).
- Building Slack chatbot with Slack Bolt to monitor the service when deploying.

Freelance Software/Al Engineer

<u>Upwork</u> | International market | Nov 2022 - March 2023

- Develop software tools and utilities (e.g. syntax checker, trading probabilistic calculator, simple compilers and algorithms to solve large data problems).
- Build dashboard to visualize data, analyze and provide insight from the dashboard.
- Build machine learning models and fine-tune them to achieve a good measure metrics (accuracy, F1-score, etc).

Blockchain Developer Intern

VBPO JSC | Vietnam market | May 2022 - Oct 2022

- Research blockchain technologies and develop a blockchain-based application for digitalizing real estate.
- Focus mainly in backend development and smart contract implement with NEAR and Aurora Engine.

Programming Lecturer

Teky Academy | Vietnam market | Nov 2020 - Apr 2022

- Teach programming & STEAM for children in the age of 12 to 18 year old.
- Tutoring in algorithms using Python language & application development with frameworks (e.g. Python Turtle, PyQt5, Wordpress)

Mobile/Backend Developer

CodeNGreen Ltd | Vietnam market | July 2018 - Nov 2019

 Develop mobile application and backend servers which connect with IoT device to automatically water gradens.

Embedded Software Researcher

FPO VN | Vietnam/Korea market | Apr 2018 - June 2018

- Research embedded systems and write instruction blogs about designing softwares with IoT devices.
- Setup machines for Al labs (e.g. Raspberry Pi, 3D Printer).

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

Naver Blog (블로그)

Naver Vietnam | Team size: 9

Blog on map

- Design & implement the map feature for the Naver Blog service, which display over **184M user's blogs** on Naver Map and Google map.
- Migrate data from a source-of-truth using Kafka which can serve up-to 1000 message per second.
- Optimized the maximum page-fetch latency from 30 seconds to 3 seconds (avg latency 0.3s) for a page with 65.000+ map locations.

Blog RSS

- Implement RSS feed feature to provide top 50 latest posts of a user.
- Leveraging Vitess database to provide a more highavailability system and sharding 4TB data of posts.
- **Techstack:** Spring boot, K8S, ELK, Kafka, Redis, Nginx, SonarQube, Zookeeper, Vitess, CQRS pattern.

Naver BBoom (岩)

Naver Vietnam | Team size: 9

- Maintain a social network service for more than 6M users to shares humor and meme posts.
- Migrate system from Server-side rendering (SSR) to Client-side rendering (CSR) without downtime.
- Optimized many features of the legacy system (e.g. search feature, favorite post feature).
- **Tech stack:** Spring Boot, Spring Integration, Spring Batch, K8S, ELK, Redis, Slave-master MySQL, Nginx, Jenkins, HDFS, SonarQube, Zookeeper.

MYPT Real Estate

VPBO JSC | Team size: 4

- Design a system that using Blockchain technology to digitalize the real estate.
- Develop smart contracts using NEAR protocol & Aurora engine.
- Achieving the 3rd prize in GFS Blockchain Hackathon with **award of 1000\$**.
- **Tech stack:** NEAR protocol, Aurora Engine, Postgres, ReactJS, ExpressJS, Ant Design, Tailwind.

Huimitu

University | Team size: 6

- Develop an e-commerce website that **integrates payment methods** (e.g. Momo, Paypal).
- **Applied machine learning** for the related-product recommendation.
- Integrating with OpenRouteService to do geocoding
- Apply automation test with Katalon application.
- **Tech stack:** ReactJS, ExpressJS, KNIME, Tableau, Postgres, Heroku, Vercel, OpenRouteService, Katalon, Figma, Cloudinary.
- Youtube: Huimitu youtube

PUBLICATION

Unifying Global and Local Scene Entities Modelling for Precise Action Spotting

I<u>EEE IJCNN 2024</u> | Yokohama Japan

- Propose a method to improve current action spotting vision models by unifying global and local feature.
- The method not only help Al model improving the accuracy but also more explainable
- By applying the GLIP a zero-shot learning model of Google, the method can apply on arbitrary sports.
- GitHub: Github repository

Product recommendation for Huimitu ecommerce using Association Rule with KNIME

Medium | Low code for datascience

• Story about how I built a recommendation system for an e-commerce (named Huimitu) system, using KNIME.

MACHINE LEARNING PROJECTS

GAN Image-patching Inpainting

Jowork

- Develop & train a generative adversarial network (GAN) model to patch the missing hole in the given image using Tensorflow.
- Collect data by capturing real-life image and create pipeline to augment the image for training phase.
- Fine-tune the model to achieve the best result.

Deep Q-learning Snake

University

- Develop Snake game as an environment to train the DQN model and integrate it with the A* algorithm using Pytorch.
- Achieve the **1st prize** in a university contest which to find the solution for Snake game.
- GitHub: DQN Snake repository

Dog and cat classification and detection

University

- Build CNN models to classify an input image whether it contains cat or dog
- Fine-tune model with different networks (VGG, ResNet) to achieve the highest performance
- Apply sliding window technics to detect the position of the classified animal on the image
- Kaggle: Kaggle notebooks
- GitHub: GitHub repository

WORKING REFERENCES

Mr. Le Ngoc Hieu

Team leader

Email: ngochieubmt@gmail.com Phone: (+84) 907 769 634

Mr. Tran Cong Thuc

Backend engineer

Email: thucctin@gmail.com Phone: (+84) 976 335 341